<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>physics on Joachim Weise</title>
    <link>https://joachimweise.github.io/tags/physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in physics on Joachim Weise</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>youremail@domain.com (Joachim Weise)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>youremail@domain.com (Joachim Weise)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joachimweise.github.io/tags/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraunhofer Lines</title>
      <link>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-10-20-fraunhofer-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Joachim Weise)</author>
      <guid>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-10-20-fraunhofer-lines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fraunhofer lines are a set of spectral absorption lines named after the German physicist Joseph von Fraunhofer (1787–1826). The lines were originally observed as dark features in the optical spectrum of the Sun by the English chemist William Hyde Wollaston in 1802. In 1814, Fraunhofer independently rediscovered the lines and began to systematically study and measure the wavelengths where these features are observed. He mapped over 570 lines, designating the principal features (lines) with the letters A through K and weaker lines with other letters. Modern observations of sunlight can detect many thousands of lines. About 45 years later Kirchhoff and Bunsen noticed that several Fraunhofer lines coincide with characteristic emission lines identified in the spectra of heated elements. It was correctly deduced that dark lines in the solar spectrum are caused by absorption by chemical elements in the solar atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derivative (or Tangent Map)</title>
      <link>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-05-01-derivative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Joachim Weise)</author>
      <guid>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-05-01-derivative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a follow-on from a previous post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-03-12-tangent-space/&#34;&gt;tangent spaces&lt;/a&gt;. It is part of a series of posts that I write on the basics of differential or Riemannian geometry, providing the necessary background for reading some of the more advanced textbooks on general relativity. I will introduce the derivative of a smooth map between manifolds and work a little bit with the definition(s) to become familiar with the thicket of mathematical notation. Then I narrow in on the special case where &lt;span  class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(f\)&lt;/span&gt; is a real-valued function, introduce the notions of dual space and covectors, and finally show the connection to the differential known from basic calculus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangent Spaces</title>
      <link>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-03-01-tangent-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Joachim Weise)</author>
      <guid>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-03-01-tangent-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a follow-on from a previous post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-01-12-differential-manifolds/&#34;&gt;differentiable manifolds&lt;/a&gt;. It is part of a series of posts that I write on the basics of differential or Riemannian geometry, providing the necessary background for reading some of the more advanced textbooks on general relativity. The following posts will cover tensors, covariant derivatives and parallel transport. The presentation will be informal, focusing mostly on motivation, definitions and key facts, not on mathematical proofs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differentiable Manifolds</title>
      <link>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-01-12-differential-manifolds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Joachim Weise)</author>
      <guid>https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-01-12-differential-manifolds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post in short series that I write on the basics of differential or  Riemannian geometry. Differential geometry is a key mathematical foundation of general relativity, and the terminology presented here is a prerequisite for reading some of the more advanced textbooks, such as the ones by Carroll, MTW, Wald, Straumann or Hawking/Ellis. Here I start with differentiable manifolds. The following posts will cover &lt;a href=&#34;https://joachimweise.github.io/post/2020-03-01-tangent-space/&#34;&gt;tangent spaces&lt;/a&gt;, tensors, covariant derivatives and parallel transport. The presentation will be informal, focusing mostly on motivation, definitions and key facts, not on mathematical proofs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>